Harshitha Pasem

Denton, TX 76201 | (940)-843-5970 | harshithapasem@gmail.com

https://github.com/Harshithapasem | www.linked.com/in/harshithapasem https://www.kaggle.com/harshithapasam

CAREER SUMMARY

Enthusiastic Data Science graduate student at University of North Texas graduating in May 2024. Seeking an internship opportunity as Data Scientist/ Data Analyst which focuses on workflows, analyzing large datasets, and creating data visualizations. Skilled at data centric programming languages like Python, data wrangling, SQL, data analytics, data visualization and machine learning algorithms. Almost two years of experience working as an application development associate and flexible in SQL and Data Visualization tools in IT companies with some Power BI Tools.

EDUCATION

University of North Texas | Denton, TX

Master of Science, Data Science

GPA: 3.8

Expected: May 2024

Relevant Course Work: Data Visualization, Data Analytics, Datasets, Data Mining, Data Discovery Knowledge, Machine Learning, Data Modeling/Management (back-end development), Databases.

Vignan's Institute of Engineering for Women | Visakhapatnam, AP

Oct 2020

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Engineering (JNTUK accredited)

GPA: 3.49

Relevant Course Work: Programming Language (C, C++, Python, R, Java), Computer Networks, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence.

SKILLS

Machine Learning Algorithms: Linear Regression, Random Forest, Naive Bayesian, Decision Tree, Support Vector Machine, K-Mean, KNN, Neural Network.

Deep Learning: Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN), Artificial Neural Network (ANN).

Software: Tableau, TensorFlow, MySQL, Microsoft Office Suite (Excel, Word, Power Point), Android Studio, D365, Anaconda.

Statistics: Descriptive Statistics, Probability Theory, Time Series Analysis, Bayesian statistics.

Soft Skills: Self-motivated, Organized, Time Management, Independent and Flexible, Communication Skills,

Programming Languages: Python (Intermediate), JSON, APIs, R (Beginner), .NET with MVC(Beginner), data Wrangling, exploratorydata analysis, data mining and Machine Learning.

Certifications: Google Certified Data Analytics, Microsoft Power Platforms Fundamentals, SQL for Data Analytics, Tableau Certification from Intern Shala.

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

Wills Library | Denton, Texas, US

May 2023 - Present

Student Assistant: customer service, check-in, and check-out books

- Providing Customer Services for the patrons using library resources.
- Helping faculty and other patrons by connecting them to resources and assistance in support of their education and research.
- > Checking out the resources for the patrons.
- Helping patrons to understand the library policies and resources.

Frisco Landing Library | Frisco, Texas, US

Jan 2023 – May 2023

Student Assistant: customer service, check-in, and check-out books

- Providing Customer Services for the patrons using library resources.
- ➤ Helping faculty and other patrons by connecting them to resources and assistance in support of their education and research.
- Checking out the resources for the patrons.
- Helping patrons to understand the library policies and resources.

Accenture | Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Nov 2020 – Aug 2022

Application Development Associate: learned D365, Power Bi tools, System Engineer Tasks

- ➤ Worked on Dynamics 365 with Power BI Tools with 7 clients.
- > Created a positive impact for the clients with Customer Service.
- > Improving the data quality by following data analytics techniques such as descriptive analysis, predictive analysis
- > Worked on system engineer tasks regularly and involved in technical development team.
- Apart from issues in development, also had competition to showcase communication skills, where stood seventh position.
- Assisted internal clients with software operation, troubleshooting system setup issues and developing software tailored to business needs.
- Got recognized by manager for work delivering to team.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Traffic Sign Detection using Convolutional Neural Networks

Nov 2019 – Feb 2020

Python Libraries such as NumPy, Pandas, matplotlib, TensorFlow, sklearn, Keras, created an interface using tkinter to predict the traffic sign to which class does it belongs while testing.

Link: <a href="https://github.com/Harshithapasem/Python/tree/main/trafficsignusingcnn-master/trafficsi

Walmart Sales Prediction

Oct 2022-Dec 2022

Python Libraries such as NumPy, Pandas, merging and grouping using machine learning models to predict their sales.

Link: https://github.com/Harshithapasem/Python/tree/main/Walmart Sales Prediction

Walmart Visualization in Tableau

Nov 2022 - Dec 2022

Created innovative sheets, dashboards, and stories to give insights for the stores data using Tableau, developed machinemodels with the perfect fit to predict the future sales.

Link: https://github.com/Harshithapasem/Tableau/tree/main/Walmart%20Visualization

Restaurant Management System

Mar 2023-May 2023

Creating databases, tables by joining the tables and getting the queries

Link: https://github.com/Harshithapasem/SQL/tree/main/Restaurant%20Management%20System

Paper Publications

Traffic Sign Detection using Convolutional Neural Networks

Jun 2020

In this paper we have published about how the traffic sign are been detected using convolutional neural networks Link: http://www.ijcst.com/vol11/issue2/7-pasem-harshitha.pdf

Competitions

Prediction Competition – Bike Sharing Demands

Oct - Nov 2022

I stood in third place in the competition among 27 teams and used the machine learning algorithm to solve the given problem.

Link: https://www.kaggle.com/competitions/info5502-bike-sharing-demand

Regression Competition – Data Rush: UNT's Ultimate Regression Challenge

Mar 2023- Apr2023

In this competition we need regression models. Stood **Third** in this competition.

Link: https://www.kaggle.com/competitions/data-rush-unts-ultimate-regression-challenge

LEADERSHIP & STUDENT ORGANIZATIONS

Indian Student Association (ISA)
Data Science Organization
Women in Computing World

Oct 2022—Present Aug 2022—Present Jan 2023--Present